Guide to the Chancellor of the University of Pittsburgh, Wesley W. Posvar, Administrative Files, 1967-1991 UA.2.10.1967-1991
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Academic Year 1979/80, XIII.
  - University Boards, Committee and Memberships, 1979-1980; 3.0.
    - University Senate, 1979-1980; 3.5.
      - University Senate - General (Box 18, Folder 3.5)
        Edison Montgomery appointed to fill Nathan Stark's position on Senate Council, October 31, 1980; Memorandum on Administrative Resource Persons to Senate Committees; Appointment of eight members to Senate Council and four in University Senate, July 31, 1979; General Meetings of the University Senate, July 25, 1979; Proposed Amendment to Faculty Reviews and Appeals Principles and Procedures concerning Tenure and Academic Freedom Committee, July 19, 1979; Early Retirement; Chancellors remarks, January 16, 1980; Report of the Senate Committee for elections, 1980-1981; General Announcements of the Chancellor at March 20, 1980 Meeting; Report of the Chancellor at October 26, 1979 Meeting; and University Senate Annual Report, 1978-1979.
      - Faculty Assembly (Box 18, Folder 3.5a)
      - Budget Policies Committee (Box 18, Folder 3.5b)
      - Educational Policies Committee (Box 18, Folder 3.5c)
      - Athletics Committee (Box 18, Folder 3.5d)
      - Library Committee (Box 18, Folder 3.5e)
      - University Senate Meetings (Box 18, Folder 3.5f)
      - External Studies Program (UCEP) (Box 18, Folder 3.5.1)
        "Pennarama" and the Instructional Systems Development Service (ISDS), May 14, 1980; Vital statistics on the state of UCEP, February 1980; Schedule for Robert Pringle to Prepare for External Evaluation of UCEP, October 11, 1979; Letter sent to all Pennsylvania legislators who represent districts in which two or more UCEP students reside, October 1, 1979; and "What Institutions of Higher Education Should Know About Television As They Enter The 1980s" by Michael B. Spring.
      - University Athletic Committee (UAC) (Box 18, Folder 3.5.2)
        Membership List; Committee Recommendations, January 1980; Varsity Athletic Catastrophe Accident Insurance, May 15, 1980; Professor George Shames will serve as Acting Chairman of the UAC, December 18, 1979; Bruce D. Murphy and Professor Edward F. Cooke, Department of Political Science, invited to become members of the UAC, September 11, 1979); Mr. J. Lawrence McBride, Class of 1950, will be the representative to the General Alumni Association of UAC, July 2, 1979; and UAC Meetings.
    - Official Memberships, 1979-1980; 3.6.
      - Allegheny Conference on Community Development (ACCD) (Box 18, Folder 3.6.1)
        Conference Activities in support of the Pittsburgh Public Schools, June 23, 1980; Robert Pease, Executive Director of ACCD, will chair the citizens' advisory committee on school desegregation, January 1980; Federal Financial Assistance for Plant Expansion, January 1980; Annual Awards Luncheon, September 21, 1979; Dr. Posvar appointed a member of the Allegheny Conference Subcommittee on Health Services, January 23, 1980; ACCD Contributions, Health Policy Institute; Executive Committee Meetings; ACCD Officers and Members of the Executive Committee, 1979-1980; ACCD General Operating Fund, 1980; Budget and 1979 Statement of Income and Expenses; Articles of Association of The Pennsylvania Business Council; Proposal of Intergovernmental Cooperation In The Allegheny Region; and Employment Committee.
      - National Association of State Universities and Land-Grant Colleges (NASULGC) (Box 19, Folder 3.6.3)
        Critical Votes on FY 1981 Budget Resolution; Updating NASULGC Legislative Network, September 17, 1980; Dr. Posvar and Provost Smith designated voting members of Urban Affairs Committee with "A Proposal For A Division of Urban Affairs"; Dr. J.R. Quatroche accepts reappointment to the Committee on Collective Negotiations and Dr. Posvar accepts reappointment to the Committees on Intercollegiate Athletics and Health Policy for 1980; End of Year Report, November 20, 1979; House Action on Higher Education Act, October 24, 1979; Official delegates from Pitt for the 93rd Annual Convention; Minutes of Executive Committee Meetings; NASULGC Division of Agriculture, Directory of Officers and Committees, 1980; and 1979-1980 Student Charges at State and Land-Grant Universities.
      - NASULGC/AAU Joint Health Policy Committee (Box 19, Folder 3.6.3a)
      - NASULGC Circular Letters (Box 19, Folder 3.6.3b)
      - Pittsburgh Convention and Visitors Center (PCVC) (Box 19, Folder 3.6.4)
      - Pittsburgh Symphony Board (Box 19, Folder 3.6.5)
      - Regional Industrial Development Corporation of Southwestern Pennsylvania (RIDC) (Box 19, Folder 3.6.7)
      - United Nations Association of Pittsburgh (Box 19, Folder 3.6.8)
      - WQED Board of Directors and Committees (Box 19, Folder 3.6.9)
      - WQED, Metropolitan Pittsburgh (Box 19, Folder 3.6.9a)
      - Public Broadcasting, Inc. (Box 19, Folder 3.6.9b)
      - United Nations University, American Council (Box 19, Folder 3.6.16)
        Thank you note from Jim Hester, Rector of United Nations University; American Council for UN University Memo of August 8, 1979 and Council letter to Secretary Vance of August 6, 1979; "The future of the Council," August 8, 1979; Executive Meeting, December 20, 1979; United Nations Newsletters; "UNU: The Fourth Year," 1978-1979; and UNU World Hunger Programme, April 1980.
    - Institutional Memberships, 1979-1980; 3.7.
      - Institute of International Education (IIE) Membership Renewal (Box 20, Folder 3.7)
      - American Council on Education (ACE) (Box 20, Folder 3.7.1)
        Institutional Seminar on Current OFCCP Enforcement Activity, May 21, 1980; Federal Financial Aid Programs and Student Aid; 1979-1980 Supplemental Education Opportunity Grant allocations; ACE negotiations with the three music licensing organizations: ASCAP, BMI, and SESAC; Dr. Elizabeth Baranger and Mrs. Anne Levenson nominated to participate in the May 21-22, 1980 Forum sponsored by ACE on Education Office of Women in Higher Education to aid in the advancement of women in academic administration; Statement issued by the Office on Self-Regulation Initiatives on transfer and award of credit, February 26, 1980; "The Faculty Handbook Revision," February 15, 1980; ACE and Higher Education Management Institute (HEMI); Policy Guidelines for refund of Student Charges; ACE Institute for College and University Administrators 1980 Programs; ACE Annual Meeting, Houston, TX, October 31 - November 2, 1979; Visiting Executives Program; "President's Letter," July-September 1979.
      - ACE Fellows Program (Box 20, Folder 3.7.1a)
      - ACE Business Higher Education Program (Box 20, Folder 3.7.1b)
      - ACE Forum Executive Program, Chairman Posvar (Box 20, Folder 3.7.1c)
      - ACE Vail, Colorado Seminar (Box 20, Folder 3.7.1d)
      - Business Higher Education Forum Meetings (Box 20, Folder 3.7.1e-3.7.1f)
      - ACE Higher Education and National Affairs (Box 21, Folder 3.7.1g)
      - Pennsylvania Association of Colleges and Universities (PACU) (Box 21, Folder 3.7.4)
        PACU Officers for 1979-1980; State Appropriations Update, June 23, 1980; Survey of Tuition and Fees; Unemployment Compensation Alert with Nonprofessional unemployment compensation, June 1980; Notes of the Special PACU Executive Committee Meeting with Secretary of Education, Dr. Robert Scanlon, Held at The Temple University Center City Facility, May 23, 1979; Special Report of Legislative Activities, April 30, 1980; Special Report on Efforts of the Coalition to defeat HB 1, "A Proposal to Amend the State Constitution to Limit State and Local Spending"; Congratulatory letter to Dr. T. Sherman Stanford on his completion of first three years as PACU's Secretariat, March 1980; Reexamination of PACU's structure and priorities in the next decade, February 29, 1980; U.S. Third Circuit Court of Appeals Rules in favor of Delaware Valley College and PACU Amicus Brief, December 20, 1979; Dr. Posvar invited to serve as member of a committee to re-examine the future of higher education planning regions and their funding, November 20, 1979; Dr. Posvar to serve as Chairman of the Commission on Commonwealth Universities; Status of the Efforts by the Pennsylvania House of Representatives to abolish the State Board of Education, October 16, 1979; Education Congress; PACU Public Relations Workshops, October 1, 1979; Possible nominees for the State Board of Education; HR 4949 Bill now before Congress to adversely alter educational admissions testing, September 4, 1979; A guide to further analysis and utilization of the Study of Academic Programs, August 13, 1979; and 1979-1980 State Budget Passes.
      - PACU Meetings, Legislation and Reports (Box 21, Folder 3.7.4a)
        PACU 1979 Annual Meeting; PACU Legislative Action Needed flyers; Executive Committee Meetings; PACU Survey of Student Charges, 1978-1979 vs. 1979-1980; and PACU Bulletins, "Academic Scene."
      - PACU, "The BOK Report" (Box 21, Folder 3.7.4b)
      - Pittsburgh Council on Higher Education (PCHE) (Box 21, Folder 3.7.5)
        Scheduled Meetings for Academic Year, 1980-1981; Buhl Foundation grant to PCHE, May 22, 1980; PCHE Executive Director's Annual Report, May 21, 1980; PCHE Program of Sharing Institutional Planning Experiences, Summary of Presentation by Carnegie-Mellon University and PCHE Program to Exchange Institutional Planning Information; American Experience Seminar, September 14, 1979; Welcome letter to Dr. Ronald V. Wells, Interim President of Pittsburgh Theological Seminary, September 7, 1979; and PCHE President's Council Meetings.
      - University Health Center (UHC) (Box 21, Folder 3.7.8)
        The use of the Lothrop-Darragh block, February 7, 1980; Health Center Facilities Program, January 31, 1980; Policy statement on ambulatory care facility development, November 1979; Mr. Leon Falk will continue to be the University's official trustee representative on the Health Center Board and its Executive Committee, October 25, 1979; Letter from Dr. Posvar regarding possibility of conflict of interest involving Trustees or Officers of the UHC, October 9, 1979; Extent of University's Contribution to Proposed Health Policy Institute, September 26, 1979; UHCP Planning Process and Joint Conference Committee; Pittsburgh Skin and Cancer Foundation will move to the University of Pittsburgh, August 30, 1979; Programs for Obstetrics, Neonatology and Gynecology; "UHCP Special Report"; "UHCP Building and Spacial Relationship Study"; and Ketchum MacLeod and Grove public relations proposal for Pitt.
      - UHC Board of Trustees, Fourth Quarter Meeting, December 27, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 3.7.8a)
      - UHC Board of Trustees, Annual Meeting, September 12, 1979 (Box 22, Folder 3.7.8b)
      - UHC Operating Account, President's Office, Balance Sheet and Controller's Committee, and Minutes of Budget Hearings Central Services (Box 22, Folder 3.7.8c)
      - Presbyterian Hospital Proposed Budgets (Box 22, Folder 3.7.8e)
      - Presbyterian Hospital Board of Trustees and Executive Committee Meetings (Box 23, Folder 3.7.8f)
      - Presbyterian Hospital Executive Committee Meetings (Box 23, Folder 3.7.8g)
      - UHC - Board of Visitors (Box 23, Folder 3.7.8h)
      - Children's Hospital (Box 23, Folder 3.7.8i)
      - UHC Executive Committee Minutes (Box 23, Folder 3.7.8j)
      - UHC Administrator's Committee Minutes (Box 23, Folder 3.7.8k)
      - American Association of University Professors (AAUP) (Box 23, Folder 3.7.9)
      - American Association for Higher Education (AAHE), National Conference (Box 23, Folder 3.7.10.)
      - Association of American Universities (AAU) (Box 23, Folder 3.7.14)
        Effort Reporting; Progress Report on Accountability, May 1980; Senate Budget Resolution, April 1980; Visit of Dr. Thomas A. Bartlett. President, AAU; AAU Priorities, April 3, 1980; Nominations for NSF Director, March 27, 1980; Minutes, AAU Executive Committee Meetings; Contract no. C-PRM-7925829 for "An Exploratory Study of Needs for and Utilization of Scientific Instrumentation," February 28, 1980; G.I. Bill for Education, February 22, 1980; Health Manpower Legislation with "Statement of University Presidents Concerning Federal Health Professions Education Program"; Women in Higher Education, February 14, 1980; Patent Legislation, February 11, 1980; DOE-sponsored energy research program and Problem-Oriented University Energy Research Program; Possibility of decisive changes in Section 1203 of the Higher Education Act, November 20, 1979; 1979-1980 AAU Institutions Data Exchange with Summary of Proceedings of the March 22-23, 1979, Meeting of AAU Institutions Data Exchange Representatives; The Research Libraries Group, November 2, 1979; Review of the AAU Since the BOK Report, August 1979; AAU delegation visit to the West German Rectors Conference, June 24-29, 1979; and "University Contributions to the National Energy Program: New Knowledge, New Talent, New Integration," A Report of the Energy Research Advisory Committee AAU, September 21, 1979.
      - AAU Meeting, April 20-22, 1980 (Box 24, Folder 3.7.14a)
      - AAU Fall Membership Meeting, October 21-23, 1979 (Box 24, Folder 3.7.14b)
      - AAU Committee on Science and Research and Energy Advisory Committee (Box 24, Folder 3.7.14c)
      - Committee on Urban Program Universities (CUPU) (Box 24, Folder 3.7.14c)
        Senate Committee Report and Action on Urban Grant; Draft being prepared for the use of the Subcommittee will include a slightly modified version of S.1553, the Urban Grant University bill; Chairman William D. Ford Receives Honorary Doctorate, February 19, 1980; CUPU Members of the Board, January 21, 1980; House approval of Urban Grant, November 8, 1979; Urban Grant Mark-up, September 10, 1979; and Annual Meeting, January 19, 1980.
      - American Association of State Colleges and Universities (AASCU), Federal Program Information (Box 24, Folder 3.7.17)
    - Senior and Administrative Staff, 1979-1980; 3.8.
      - Administrative Staff (Box 24, Folder 3.8.1)
      - Senior Staff (Box 24, Folder 3.8.2)
      - Executive Staff Meetings and Action Items (Box 24, Folder 3.8.2a)
    - Memoranda to Staff, 1979-1980; 3.9.
      - Memoranda (Box 25, Folder 3.9)
        Benedum Foundation meeting, May 12, 1980; Visit to U.S. Steel, April 17, 1980; Letters for appropriations hearing in Harrisburg, March 31, 1980; Trip to Shippingport Nuclear Plant, March 31, 1980; Campaign Visit to the Buhl Foundation, February 26, 1980; Call on the Rockwell International Corp., February 26, 1980; Dravo Corp., February 20, 1980; Consolidated Gas, February 26, 1980; Mr. John Ryan, Mine Safety Apparatus, February 21, 1980; Telephone Conversation with Governor Thornburgh, December 6, 1979; The Shot Felt Around the World, Salk Vaccine announcement, December 3, 1979; Meeting with Dr. Mimi Bishop, December 1, 1979; Buck Consultants, Inc., November 30, 1979; Mr. Merle Gilliand, Pittsburgh National Bank, November 21, 1979; R.K. Mellon Foundation, November 20, 1979; Thomas Graham, Jones & Laughlin Steel Corp., November 6, 1979; Mr. Krome George, Alcoa, November 6, 1979; Meeting with Robert Dickey Regarding the Fund Development Program, October 8, 1979; Meeting with Fletcher Byrom Regarding Fund Development, October 5, 1979; David Roderick, U. S. Steel, September 24, 1979; H.J. Heinz, II, September 21, 1979; and Campaign Meeting with Donald R. Beall, Rockwell International, September 17, 1979.
    - Affirmative Action, 1979-1980; 3.10.
      - Affirmative Action - General (Box 25, Folder 3.10.)
        Lt. Charles Westbrooks and the University Community Coalition Conference, May 31, 1980; ACE is sponsoring an institutional seminar on current enforcement activities of the Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs of the Department of Labor, May 21, 1980; The Pennsylvania Human Relations Commission is the primary agency in the Commonwealth of Pennsylvania responsible for the enforcement of the state's civil rights law, May 2, 1979; Faculty and Administrative Applicant Data Forms; Affirmative Action approach in School of Library and Information Sciences, February 1980; Graduate and Professional Student Data Sheet, February 11, 1980; Budget, Office of the Chancellor, February 7, 1980; Legal Counsel should be kept fully informed of the compliance reviews, December 7, 1979; Summary Reviews of "Preserving America's Investment in Human Capital" by W. J. Minter and H. R. Bowen, December 2, 1979; Proposed Meeting to Discuss Minority Trustees' Concerns with paper "University of Pittsburgh Minority Programs FY 1975-1979"; Procedures for Advertising Staff Vacancies, October 10, 1979; Letter from American Association for Affirmative Action with pamphlet, September 24, 1979; University Policies and Procedures Related to the Affirmative Action Program; Affirmative Action Office Reorganization, September 4, 1979; Letter from HEW to determine the compliance status of Pitt in relation to the requirements of Executive Order 11246, August 14, 1979; Title IX Complaint Process, August 3, 1979; Current Status of the Department of Labor Compliance Review, July 25, 1979; Affirmative Action Policy for Recruitment, Selection, and Advancement of Personnel at Pitt; and "The Physician and the Rehabilitation Act for Disabled People."
      - Minority Programs, FY 1975-1979 (Box 25, Folder 3.10a)
      - Title IX Correspondence and Meeting with DeHart Associates (Box 25, Folder 3.10b)
      - Compliance, Reports and Meetings (Box 25, Folder 3.10c)
        Pitt is notified by National Institutes of Health, Department of Health, Education and Welfare to determine the compliance status of the University in relation to the requirements of Executive Order 11246, August 14, 1979; The Affirmative Action Program has been cited by Office of Federal Contract Compliance Programs, July 3, 1979; University Affirmative Action Committee All-Day Spring Meeting, May 15, 1980; Meeting with Area Office OFCCP - Department of Labor, March 28, 1980; and Tape Transcription of Chancellor's Report on Affirmative Action Senate Meeting, March 20, 1980.
  - Administration and Planning, 1979-1980; 4.0.
    - Administration and Planning - General, 1979-1980; 4.0.
      - University Owned Properties (Box 25, Folder 4.0a)
      - Oakland (Box 26, Folder 4.0b)
    - Facilities and Physical Plant, 1979-1980; 4.1.
      - Business and Finance (Box 26, Folder 4.1.1)
        Final installment of the $1 million award from The Japan Iron and Steel Federation, June 1980; Business and Finance Personnel Changes, June 18, 1980; Joseph A. Davis Consultants, Inc. of New York City, June 5, 1980; Varsity Athletic Catastrophe Accident Insurance, May 15, 1980; Cleanup of University Property Across from Salk Hall, May 9, 1980; Deferred Maintenance, April 16, 1980; 4200 Centre Avenue, April 9, 1980; Visit to Westinghouse Tele-Computer Center; Bureau of Mines Building, March 7, 1980; Special Properties Project Draft Proposal, January 11, 1980; Community Cablevision, November 30, 1979; The College Club, November 26, 1979; Expanded Travel Service Policy, November 1, 1979; State Draft Audit Report for 1976-1977 and 1977-1978; and "SF" Parking Lot, September 27, 1979.
      - Proposed Hotel Center (Box 26, Folder 4.1.1a)
      - Victoria Hall (Box 26, Folder 4.1.1b)
      - Bruce Hall Renovations (Box 26, Folder 4.1.1c)
      - Langley Aerodrome (Box 26, Folder 4.1.1d)
      - Medical Research Facility (Box 26, Folder 4.1.1e)
      - Bellefield and Dithridge Streets (Box 26, Folder 4.1.1f)
      - University Health Center Garage (Box 26, Folder 4.1.1g)
      - Investments (Box 26, Folder 4.1.1h)
      - Scaife Hall Security (Box 26, Folder 4.1.1i)
      - Mervis Hall Funding (Box 26, Folder 4.1.1j)
      - Lothrop-Darragh Block (Box 26, Folder 4.1.1k)
      - Carlow College Land (Box 26, Folder 4.1.1l)
      - School of Pharmacy Renovation (Box 27, Folder 4.1.1m)
      - Fitzgerald Field House Renovation (Box 27, Folder 4.1.1n)
      - Forbes Quadrangle (Box 27, Folder 4.1.1o)
      - Bellefield Boiler Agreement (Box 27, Folder 4.1.1p)
      - Prospective Parking Garage and he University (Box 27, Folder 4.1.1q)
      - Terrace Street Garage (Box 27, Folder 4.1.1r)
      - Museum, Street and Historical Markers (Box 27, Folder 4.1.1s)
      - University Suite (Box 27, Folder 4.1.1t)
      - Proxy Statements (Box 27, Folder 4.1.1u)
      - Stadium Dome (Box 27, Folder 4.1.1v)
    - Finance, 1979-1980; 4.2.
      - Commonwealth Audits and Annual Giving Fund Accounts (Box 27, Folder 4.2)
    - Treasurer, 1979-1980; 4.3.
      - Registrar (Box 27, Folder 4.3.1)
        Procedural Change, Student Resignations, June 16, 1980; Deadline for Continuing Student Registration, Fall Term, April 1, 1980; Draft Academic Calendar, December 13, 1979; Confidentiality of Student Records, November 13, 1979; Recent Phonathon Effort to Enhance Enrollment, October 12, 1979; and Final Enrollment estimates, September 1979.
      - Comptroller (Box 27, Folder 4.3.2)
        Time Schedule for July 1980 Monthly Payroll, Hourly Time Sheets, Time Certification Sheets, Certificate Payments, and Work Study Time Records, June 23, 1980; Sponsored Program Fringe Benefit Rate for 1980-1981; Social Security Tax (FICA) Exclusion for Sick Pay, May 1, 1980; State Audit, November 29, 1979; 1978-1979 Financial Report; and AAU Position paper on Recent Federal Audits, March 7, 1979.
    - Planning and Budget, 1979-1980; 4.4.
      - Planning and Budget - General (Box 27, Folder 4.4)
        Draft of questionnaire to solicit material for a ten-year report, June 23, 1980; Study of Medical Faculty Compensation, June 12, 1980; Proposed Fraternity Houses, June 2, 1980; Pennsylvania Special Olympics, May 6, 1980; Disposition of Proceeds from the Fiesta Bowl, May 6, 1980; Honeywell-Steel City Refrigeration, April 28, 1980; FY 1980-1981 Summary of Capital Projects, Planned Projects and Alteration and Renovation Projects Tentatively Approved as of April 21, 1980; Final Report of the Management Advisory Committee, March 27, 1980; Animal Care Facility; U.S. Office of Management and Budget (OMB) has revised Federal Management Circular regarding Cost Principles Applicable to Educational Institutions, February 26, 1980; Dr. Jack E. Freeman nominated to membership on the Board of Directors of the National Center for Higher Education Management Systems; Area Biohazards Committee/DNA Research, February 20, 1980; Highlights of Governor's Budget FY 1980-1981; Construction of a multi-use structure in two-block area, October 1, 1979; College and University FY 1980-1981 Budget Workshop Meetings; Authority to Approve Budget Modification Requests, September 11, 1979; Administrative Reorganization, August 1, 1979.
      - Reports and Proposals (Box 27, Folder 4.4a)
        Urban Redevelopment Assistance Grant (UDAG) proposal being developed for Oakland area; Budget Options: 1980-1985; Revision of the PRMS Manual; Organizational Review of Plant Services and Building Maintenance Division; Office of Space Management; Office of Facilities Planning; Draft, "The Improvement of Instructional Efficiency," March 1980; and Overview of Planning Process.
      - Planning Policies of the 80's (Box 27, Folder 4.4b-4.4c)
      - Budget Hearings, 1981 (Box 28, Folder 4.4d)
      - The University Plan (Box 28, Folder 4.4e)
      - National Center for Higher Education Management Systems (NCHEMS) (Box 28, Folder 4.4f)
      - Responsibility Center Plans (Box 28, Folder 4.4g)
      - University of Pittsburgh Operating Budget Requests (Box 28, Folder 4.4h)
      - Chancellor's Notes (Box 28, Folder 4.4i)
      - Planning and Budget (Box 28, Folder 4.4j)
      - Correspondence (Box 28, Folder 4.4k)
      - Beaver Valley Power Station (Box 29, Folder 4.4l)
      - Budget Presentation (Box 29, Folder 4.4m)